Guide to the Golden Gate Bridge: photographs, 1933-1937
Department of Special Collections
Golden Gate Bridge: photographs,
1933-1937
Special Collections Photo 164
Standard Oil Company of California
93 prints.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of C.D. Marx.
Scope and Content
Photographic documentation by Standard Oil Company of California of the building of The Golden Gate Bridge, San Francisco (Calif.).
Container List
- Golden Gate Bridge, San Francisco, engraving / by George C. Ashley (Page 1)
- Fabricating girders, 1933. (Page 2)
- Girders enroute to bridge-site, 1933. (Page 3)
- Fabricating girders, 1933. (Page 4)
- South abutment, 1934. (Page 5)
- [McClintic-Marshall Steel Co. girders], n.d. (Page 6)
- South abutment, 1934. (Page 7, Othertype A)
- South pier caisson - not used, 1934. (Page 7, Othertype B)
- Foundations for approach ramp, 1934. (Page 8, Othertype A)
- Gusset plate and joint, 1934. (Page 8, Othertype B)
- Showing size of girder, 1934. (Page 9, Othertype A)
- Looking down on South abutment, 1934. (Page 9, Othertype B)
- Looking down the North Tower, 1934. (Page 10, Othertype A)
- Beginning the South Tower, 1934. (Page 10, Othertype B)
- Beginning the South Tower, 1934. (Page 10, Othertype C)
- North Tower, 1934. (Page 11, Othertype A)
- North Tower - near completion, 1934. (Page 11, Othertype B)
- Beginning the South Tower, 1934. (Page 11, Othertype C)
- North Tower, 1934. (Page 12, Othertype A)
- North Tower, 1934. (Page 12, Othertype B)
- North Tower, 1934. (Page 13, Othertype A)
- North Tower, 1934. (Page 13, Othertype B)
- North Tower & South Tower caisson, 1934. (Page 14)
- North Tower, 1934. (Page 15)
- North Tower, 1934. (Page 16)
- North Tower & South Tower caisson, 1934. (Page 17)
- North approach, 1934. (Page 18)
- North Tower, 1934. (Page 19)
- Looking towards the ocean, 1934. (Page 20, Othertype A)
- [Golden Gate Bridge total project schedule], n.d. (Page 20, Othertype B)
- [Unidentified equipment], 1934. (Page 21, Othertype A)
- North Tower, 1935. (Page 21, Othertype B)
- South abutment, 1935. (Page 22)
- Looking South to North, 1935. (Page 23)
- South abutment construction pylon, 1935. (Page 24)
- South abutment, 1935. (Page 25)
- South Tower, 1935. (Page 26)
- South Tower, 1935. (Page 27)
- South Tower, 1935. (Page 28)
- Prepatory to cable-spinning, 1935. (Page 29)
- View - South to North, 1935. (Page 30, Othertype A)
- Prepatory to cable-spinning, 1935. (Page 30, Othertype B)
- Cable spinning apparatus atop the North Tower, 1935. (Page 31)
- Spun cable, 1935. (Page 32)
- [Spun cable], 1936 Apr. (Page 33)
- [Spun cable], 1936 May (Page 34)
- [Spun cable], 1936 Mar. (Page 35)
- Cable spinning 1936 July (Page 36)
- [Cable spinning] (Page 37)
- [Cable spinning] (Page 38)
- [Cable spinning] (Page 39, Othertype A)
- [Cable spinning] (Page 39, Othertype B)
- [Cable spinning] (Page 40)
- China Clipper over South Tower, 1935 Nov. 22 (Page 41)
- [Panoramic view of Golden Gate Bridge, facing North] (Page 42, Othertype A)
- [Panoramic view of Golden Gate Bridge, facing West] (Page 42, Othertype B)
- [Panoramic view of Golden Gate Bridge, facing West] (Page 43, Othertype A)
- [Panoramic view of Golden Gate Bridge, facing North] (Page 43, Othertype B)
- [Panoramic view of Golden Gate Bridge, facing East] (Page 44, Othertype A)
- [Panoramic view of Golden Gate Bridge, facing North] (Page 44, Othertype B)
- [Golden Gate Bridge as seen from above] (Page 45)
- [Golden Gate Bridge as seen from South abutment], 1935 (Page 46)
- [Golden Gate Bridge as seen from South abutment] (Page 47)
- [Aerial view of Golden Gate Bridge and San Francisco, facing North] (Page 48, Othertype A)
- [Golden Gate Bridge] (Page 48, Othertype B)
- [Aerial view of Golden Gate Bridge and San Francisco, facing South] (Page 49, Othertype A)
- [Aerial view of Golden Gate Bridge and San Francisco, facing South] (Page 49, Othertype B)
- [Golden Gate Bridge and San Francisco as seen from deck of a ferry, facing West] (Page 50, Othertype A)
- [Golden Gate Bridge and San Francisco as seen from deck of a boat, facing West] (Page 50, Othertype B)
- [Aerial view of Golden Gate Bridge showing cable spinning] (Page 51)
- Placing roadway girders, 1936 (Page 52)
- [Placing roadway girders], 1936 (Page 53)
- Safety net, 1936 (Page 54)
- Safety net, 1936 (Page 55, Othertype A)
- Safety net, 1936 (Page 55, Othertype B)
- Roadway growing from South Tower, 1936 (Page 56, Othertype A)
- Roadway growing from South Tower, 1936 (Page 56, Othertype B)
- [Roadway growing from South Tower], 1936 (Page 57, Othertype A)
- [Roadway growing from South Tower], 1936 (Page 57, Othertype B)
- [Safety net], 1936 (Page 58, Othertype A)
- [Ship passing underneat bridge], 1936 (Page 58, Othertype B)
- [Construction worker working on roadway], 1936 (Page 59)
- Closing the span, 1936 (Page 60, Othertype A)
- Closing the span, 1936 (Page 60, Othertype B)
- Closing the span, 1936 (Page 61)
- Closing the span, 1936 (Page 62, Othertype A)
- Closing the span, 1936 (Page 62, Othertype B)
- Closing the span, 1936 (Page 63, Othertype A)
- Closing the span, 1936 (Page 63, Othertype B)
- Empress of Britain showing ample clearance, 1937 Apr. (Page 64)
- [Golden Gate Bridge as seen from shore near South abutment] (Page 65)
- [Golden Gate Bridge as seen from above during construction of roadway] (Page 66)
- [Golden Gate Bridge as seen from Marin headlands] (Page 67)